

Pasadena and Irvine, CA

% jayesswang.com

in @jayesswang

SUMMARY

A creative storyteller, visual strategist, and empathetic advocate of user-centered experiences that align with business goals.

A perceptive, adaptable, and tech savvy ENTP-A (Myers-Briggs) leveraging a 20-yrs work history in multiple industries and roles in the USA and Asia. Able to analyze and solve a problem from multiple angles with a global perspective.

DESIGN PROCESS

Interviews Focus groups Survevs Competitive analysis User research Card sorting Info architecture Flow diagrams Sketches Wireframes Rapid prototyping **Usability testing** Heuristic evaluation

TOOLS

Figma Sketch Invision Adobe CC UsabilityHub UserTesting HTML / CSS / JavaScript Github G-Suite

LANGUAGE

Mandarin Chinese

RECENT PROJECTS

WHAT DO YOU MEME?TM MOBILE GAME | view case study

Convert a popular tabletop game for adults into a mobile game. Techniques used: online surveys, field study (observe real-time game play), contextual inquiry, card sorting, storyboarding, A/B testing, moderated usability test, Tools used: G-Suite (Forms, Sheet), Figma, UsabilityHub, Loom, YouTube.

IW PORTFOLIO | view case study

Hand code a responsive portfolio website from scratch and host it on GitHub Pages. Tools include Figma, UsabilityHub, HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Github.

BOXLY | view case study

Design an SaaS that allows users to collect, store, and share info all from one place. Techniques used: online surveys, user stories, user flows, A/B testing, unmoderated usability testing (wireframes & mockups). Tools used: G-Suite (Forms, Sheet), Draw.io, Balsamiq, Sketch, InVision, UserTesting.

EXPERIENCE

UX DESIGN APPRENTICE | BLOC.IO | Remote

2018

Complete an 8-mth apprenticeship under an experienced UX professional. Participate remotely in daily design critiques and weekly design webinars: collaborate w/ my cohort on Slack; and complete 3 projects.

PHOTOGRAPHER | JW PHOTOGRAPHY | Los Angeles

2008 - 2018

Notable clients include: Bebe, HauteLook (Nordstrom), Halston, Ozsale.

IN-HOUSE PHOTOGRAPHER | FOREVER 21

2013 - 2017

Second-in-command to photography supervisor; **train** new photographers: some duties exceed original job title and description. Collaborate across departments: demonstrate corporate diplomacy.

WEB PRODUCER | KAC MEDIA | Los Angeles

2010 - 2011

Produce content, research the story, write scripts, conduct interviews, create video rough drafts. Start-up work culture with small, nimble, and fluid teams. Wear multiple hats, assisting as needed in all tasks from pre- to post-production.

SENIOR EDITOR | ENVISION MBA | Taipei, Taiwan

2006 - 2010

Asia's #1 education consultancy tailoring **branding & strategy** for prospective applicants to the **top 50 MBA programs** worldwide. Hundreds of successful student placements at: INSEAD, HEC Paris, London Business School, Wharton, Sloan, Columbia, Oxford, Haas, and others.

EDUCATION

BLOC.IO | UX DESIGN APPRENTICESHIP

2018

Certificate in UX Design

LOS ANGELES CENTER OF PHOTOGRAPHY

2012

Certificate in Commercial Photography

UNIVERSITY OF SOUTHERN CALIFORNIA (USC)

2006

B.A. in English & Creative Writing / Minor in Music Business